## HEATHER LIEDER

16 West 6th Avenue | Longmont, CO 80501 | heatherslieder@gmail.com | 303.601.6631

#### CAREER OVERVIEW

10+ years of successful sales and marketing experience in multi-million dollar personal care and lifestyle brands with special expertise in the natural/organic market. Expertise with business start-up, account management, forecasting and budgeting, sales goal development and execution, strategic market planning, broker/rep management, product and brand development, packaging, product launch, promotion and merchandising.

#### HISTORY OF EXPERIENCE

## LIEDERSHIP CONSULTING GROUP | Boulder, CO | Feb 2014 – Present Founder & Business Development Consultant

- Develop and implement sales and marketing strategies for clients, including: product introductions, merchandising and placement opportunities, revenue targets, pricing and promotions.
- Advise clients on general business operations, including account management, broker/rep management, forecasting and budgeting, sales goal development and employee retention programs.
- Current clients include: Clean George moisturizing and soothing skin sticks, Olomomo Nut Company, Colorado Aromatics skincare, Rosalee's Pizzeria, Colorado Beer Trail and Paddleboards USA.

# PANGEA ORGANICS | Boulder, CO | <u>pangeaorganics.com</u> | Jan 2013 – Feb 2014 Chief Operating Officer

- Executed the strategic vision of the company's Board of Directors and Chief Executive Officer focusing on the establishment and optimization of day-to-day operations in the company.
- All internal department heads responsible for delivering services reported to the COO; these include: Customer Service, Sales, Marketing, Operations, and Research & Development.
- > Developed and initiated Pangea's sales & marketing strategies, including: product development, product introductions, placement opportunities, revenue targets, pricing and promotions.
- Responsible for vendor relations, acquisition and management, including: manufacturing, fulfillment, enterprise software, general counsel, public relations and creative agencies.
- > Implemented the launch of Pangea's direct sales division and navigated the exit of the retail sales division.

## PANGEA ORGANICS | Boulder, CO | <u>pangeaorganics.com</u> | Jan 2010 – Dec 2012 **Sales & Marketing Director**

- > Achieved a 180% average increase in Whole Foods Market Rocky Mountain Region sales year over year from 2011 2012 within budget.
- > Achieved 25% average increase in overall sales year over year from 2010 2011 within budget.
- > Developed and initiated Pangea's sales & marketing strategies, including: product introductions, placement opportunities, revenue targets, pricing and promotions.
- > Responsible for the management of public relations, website design and online marketing agencies.

## **HEATHER LIEDER - PAGE 2 OF 4 (CONTINUED)**

PANGEA ORGANICS | Boulder, CO | <u>pangeaorganics.com</u> | Apr 2004 – Dec 2009 **Marketing Director** 

- > Achieved 200% average increase in sales year over year from 2004 2008 within budget.
- Responsible for the launch of Pangea into national, multi-unit chains and cross-media platforms, including but not limited to: Whole Foods Market, Sephora, Regis Corporation, Macy's, Nordstrom and the Home Shopping Network.
- > Developed and initiated Pangea's sales & marketing strategies, including: product introductions, placement opportunities, revenue targets, pricing and promotion.
- > Instrumental in securing key accounts, including but not limited to a \$2.5 million account.
- > Responsible for the management of public relations, website design and online marketing agencies.

## COMMUNITY FOOD SHARE | Boulder, CO | <u>communityfoodshare.org</u> | Aug 2003 – Apr 2004 **Assistant Development Director**

- > Supported the Development Director in the overall management and achievement of annual fundraising efforts in the amount of \$1 million.
- > Led marketing communications to raise hunger awareness in Boulder and Broomfield Counties.
- Responsible for donor relations, including new donor acquisition and retention programs.
- > Directed content and creative for special events, direct mail campaigns, website and newsletter.
- Managed fundraising events and donor receptions; solicited corporate sponsors and in-kind donors.

### COMMUNITY FOOD SHARE | Boulder, CO | <u>communityfoodshare.org</u> | Dec 2002 – Aug 2003 **Development Assistant**

- Grant-writing efforts resulted in \$17,000 in 2003.
- Local public relations efforts resulted in a 75% pick-up rate in 2003.
- Achieving annual savings of \$3,000 in direct mail costs by purging donor database of inactive donors from 10,000 records to 8,500 active donors,
- Managed donor relations, including new donor acquisition and retention programs.
- > Generated new donor reports and formulated direct mail analysis for CEO.
- Supported fundraising events and donor receptions; solicited corporate sponsors and in-kind donors.

### FUNDACION AMISTAD | East Hampton, NY | <u>fundacionamistad.org</u> | May 2002 – Oct 2002 **Program Manager**

- > Secured \$250,000 to be awarded over two years, the organization's largest grant to date.
- Instrumental in securing \$75,000, the organization's second largest grant to date.
- Managed the organization's first conference in Cuba, during the embargo when relations between the United States and Cuba were limited at best, with more than 120 museum curators from around the world.
- > Collaborated in writing and editing of the organization's Annual Report.

## **HEATHER LIEDER - PAGE 3 OF 4 (CONTINUED)**

### RISING TIDE STUDIOS | New York, NY | Aug 2001 – May 2002 Account / Production Manager

- Increased Annual Revenue by as much as 30% as a result of negotiating contract with a reprint services company.
- Achieved Annual Savings of \$100,000 as a result of negotiating contract with a new printer.
- ➤ Generated more than \$90,000 in online ad sales within one year in a down economy.
- Achieved Annual Savings of 12% by negotiating the company's insurance policy.
- Shortened print cycle from 28 days to 14 days.
- > Directed ad traffic for six online and two print publications; managed production schedules and acted as liaison between sales department, art department, clients and printer.
- ➤ Upheld all previous responsibilities as National Account Manager.
- Assisted in implementing the re-branding of *Silicon Alley Reporter* and navigating the launch of *Venture Reporter*.

## RISING TIDE STUDIOS | New York, NY | May 2001 – Aug 2001 National Account Manager

- ➤ Generated \$40,000 in revenue in a four-month period.
- Negotiated contracts with Biotech / Biopharma companies.
- > Initiated 50 60 sales calls per day, generated sales leads, and established an independent client pool.
- Consulted clients on marketing strategy to maximize exposure and increase response rate by utilizing our advertising vehicles.
- > Managed client accounts, insertion orders and credit card authorization forms.

### RISING TIDE STUDIOS | New York, NY | May 2000 – May 2001 Executive Research Assistant / Conference Coordinator

- > Coordinated six annual conferences with an average of 1,000 attendees and 100 speakers.
- > Established, issued and upheld deadlines for all conference materials internally / externally.
- Managed production of conference booklets; served as liaison between sales, marketing, art and conference departments to produce conference booklets.
- ➤ Headed conference online editing, including speaker biographies and head shots, publishing and guest registration.
- Identified and invited press to attend our events and interview our Editor-In-Chief & CEO; verified press credentials and authorized press attendance / interviews.
- Corresponded directly with speakers (CEOs, authors and scientists) and VIP guests.
- Coordinated and tracked speaker and VIP registration process, materials submittal (bios, head shots, etc.) and RSVP status.
- > Researched company history and executives for articles written by the Editor-In-Chief & CEO, and screened for potential event speakers.

## **HEATHER LIEDER - PAGE 4 OF 4 (CONTINUED)**

NORDEMAN GRIMM | New York, NY | Oct 1999 – Apr 2000 Office Administrator / Research Assistant

- Conducted research for high-level executive searches with annual compensation packages over \$250,000; managed unsolicited resumes and presented potential candidates to executive recruiters.
- Coded, reviewed, and selectively eliminated unsolicited resumes by function, industry and education.
- Maintained records of employee attendance, health benefits enrollment / termination, and profit sharing / shareholder information.
- Managed scheduling of conference rooms, kitchen duties, and switchboard coverage.
- > Provided additional research support, secretarial support, proofreading, and data entry.
- Directed and screened all incoming calls; greeted all guests.

#### **COMMUNITY RELATIONS**

CONSCIOUS ALLIANCE | consciousalliance.org | 2006 - Present

**Board Member & Communications Committee Chair** 

**Mission:** To support communities in crisis through hunger relief and youth empowerment.

GROWING GARDENS | growinggardens.org | 2011 - 2012

**Board Member & Marketing Committee Chair** 

Mission: To enrich the lives of our community through sustainable urban agriculture.

#### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

**Proficient in:** Microsoft Office Suite, QuickBooks Enterprise, Adobe Photoshop, Social Media, Salesforce, Lexis Nexis, File Finder, ACT and DonorQuest

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Vermont, B.A. English | 1999 Dual Minors in Sociology and Women's Studies Resident Assistant 1996 - 1998

#### REFERENCES

Furnished upon request.